<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/food_blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/food_blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-05-16T17:31:16-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food_blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Brenton Eats</title><subtitle>Enjoying food.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Le Calandre (***)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/food_blog/posts/2025-05-09-le-calandre" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Le Calandre (***)" /><published>2025-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food_blog/posts/le_calandre</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/food_blog/posts/2025-05-09-le-calandre"><![CDATA[<!--more-->

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Rating</strong></td>
      <td><em>Overall</em> <strong><em>3.6/5</em></strong>  <br /> (Taste 4/5, Presentation 4/5, Ambience 2/5)</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Cost</strong></td>
      <td>€280pp</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Location</strong></td>
      <td>Rubano, Italy</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Head Chef</strong></td>
      <td>Massimiliano Alajmo</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>TL;DR</strong></td>
      <td>modernized, authentic Italian fare elevating familiar ingredients with artistic flair</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<figure style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/restaurant.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/restaurant.jpg" alt="" style="width: 50%; display: block; margin: 0 auto;" />
  </a>
  
</figure>

<p>After an hour long ride on the Regionale train from Venice, followed by another 30 minute cab ride, one arrives at the door of Le Calandre, guarded by its large red wolf statue. The interior is dimly lit, and at each table is a divot with a ball of yarn. To get to our table, we walk past lampshades of dried stockfish skins and a large cart of cheese.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/01.jpg" alt="01: assorted breadsticks" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>01: assorted breadsticks</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/02.jpg" alt="02: pea tart, crispy olive, parmigiano reggiano bite, turmeric cheese puff, tomato cheese puff" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>02: pea tart, crispy olive, parmigiano reggiano bite, turmeric cheese puff, tomato cheese puff</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>At our seats are already placed napkins with assorted breadsticks tucked in-between. Some tasted like cheez-its, others like nutty, grain crackers, and the remaining like thick breadsticks <strong><em>(2.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Our amuse bouche was par. The pea tart had quite an herbal, rosemary-like flavor to it. The crispy deep-fried olive was interesting texturally, although I’m not a huge fan of the olive flavor. The parmigion reggiano bite was warm and savory, with a nice chew to it. The two cheese puffs had relatively similar flavors and textures (with their mild notes of their respective spice), and were melted as they sat in your mouth <strong><em>(2.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/03-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/03-01.jpg" alt="03-01: warm bread" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>03-01: warm bread</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/03-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/03-02.jpg" alt="03-02: olive oil, herb" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>03-02: olive oil, herb</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The bread dish was hurriedly brought out in the middle of us eating the amuse bouche, which I found a bit odd. Itself, it was nothing special, not piping hot. They replaced the ball in the center with the bread wrapped in a towel as a parcel. The olive oil had a sharp herb which wasn’t exceptionally tasty <strong><em>(2.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/04.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/04.jpg" alt="04: zucchini noodles, bitter root, asparagus sorbet, fava bean cream, mozzarella ball, soaked crouton" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>04: zucchini noodles, bitter root, asparagus sorbet, fava bean cream, mozzarella ball, soaked crouton</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/05.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/05.jpg" alt="05: cuttlefish, sea urchin, seaweed, potato cream, beetroot, spinach, cuttlefish ink" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>05: cuttlefish, sea urchin, seaweed, potato cream, beetroot, spinach, cuttlefish ink</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>In what was seemingly a worrying trend, our first dish came out almost immediately. The salad brought together different presentations of vegetables, most of which were chilled. There was a large crunchy brick, the fava bean cream had decent savoriness, and the soaked crouton had an almost arugula, Asian flavor. One interesting component was that the purple ball I had mistakenly presumed to be a roasted shallot; instead, it was a mozzarella ball with a red beet juice inside. Unfortunately, this salad did not taste good; it was a bit too sharp and the zucchinini noodles, among others, tasted too raw. It felt as if it was trying to do to much <strong><em>(1/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>The next dish was called “Murrina Cappuccino”, and it was stunning. Inspired by the glass from the Murano island off of Venice, the immediate visual appeal of the dish was apparent. Tasting it, the potato cream and olive oil combination was rich and buttery, while the cuttlefish chunks were perfectly cooked, with just the right amount of bite. The flavor was akin to a much elevated clam chowder. The only slight drawback was that it was a tad salty <strong><em>(4.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/06.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/06.jpg" alt="06: ricotta, tomato, mozzarella, basil, puff" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>06: ricotta, tomato, mozzarella, basil, puff</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/07-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/07-01.jpg" alt="07-01: egg shell taglietelle with aromatic herbs, cheese, egg yolk, broth with peppercorn" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>07-01: egg shell taglietelle with aromatic herbs, cheese, egg yolk, broth with peppercorn</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/07-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/07-02.jpg" alt="07-02: earplugs" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>07-02: earplugs</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>For our next dish, we are presented with adorned with text written in seaweed, “Napul’è for Alfonso Mattozzi” which is revealed to be inspired by the chef’s favorite Pizza place in Naples. The dish itself is a reconstructed pizza with puff pastry and ricotta and mozarella inside. The dish indeeds hits with warmth and familiar flavors, albeit elevated. The mozarella inside is chewy and the execution with the basil is done well, although I wish it was a tad warmer <strong><em>(3.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Following that dish, we had an egg shell taglietelle alongside a pair of earplugs! We are instructed to close our eyes when chewing to really allow the egg plant texture and sensation to be focused upon. This was a really interesting experience, and the egg shell crunch coupled with the al dente noodles really stood out. The cream was rich and the cheese and herbs are done well. The broth was soothing, herbal, and had a hint of peppercorn that numbed the throat before the next dish <strong><em>(4.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/08-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/08-01.jpg" alt="08-01: glass infused with licorice and saffron" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08-01: glass infused with licorice and saffron</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/08-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/08-02.jpg" alt="08-02: veal broth, cream, saffron, licorice, lime, grilled lemon, lemon zest" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08-02: veal broth, cream, saffron, licorice, lime, grilled lemon, lemon zest</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/08-03.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/08-03.jpg" alt="08-03: Roberto Barni's sculpture at Uffizi Gallery" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08-03: Roberto Barni's sculpture at Uffizi Gallery</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>To prepare us for the next course, we are presented with an empty glass infused with licorice and saffron which we are to smell. The dish is Le Calandre’s famous risotto, inspired by a Roberto Barni sculpture in Uffizi. This was a very complex dish, with each bite having a multitude of flavors. To start, the risotto was cooked a perfect al dente. The veal broth provided a savory base, and bites had spiciness from the licorice, sour from the citrus, and umami from the saffron. Despite mixed reviews at the table, I adored the execution <strong><em>(4.5/5)</em></strong>. Interestingly, it looked like the tables nearest us (who seemed friendly with the chef) received the remaining pots of risotto!</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/09-A.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/09-A.jpg" alt="09-A: hand-chopped Piemontese beef tartare with black truffle - balsamic vinegar, lettuce heart, oiled bread" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>09-A: hand-chopped Piemontese beef tartare with black truffle - balsamic vinegar, lettuce heart, oiled bread</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/09-B.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/09-B.jpg" alt="09-B: scorched bone marrow with calamari cream, sea urchin and Amur Dauricus caviar bruschetta, burning herbs" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>09-B: scorched bone marrow with calamari cream, sea urchin and Amur Dauricus caviar bruschetta, burning herbs</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>We had two options for the next main dish. I opted for the beef tartare with black truffle which interestingly came with no utensils, only a hand towel for afterwards. The meat felt very fresh and the balsamic vinegar and lettuce also added crispness to the dish. The aioli itself was light, although this wasn’t a stand out <strong><em>(3.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>The other option pictured was a scorched bone marrow with calamari cream and a caviar bruschetta. The marrow was described as delicious and fatty, but not greasy, while the cracker itself was elegant. The flavors were heavily inspired by the burning herb.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/10.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/10.jpg" alt="10: roasted suckling pig, chicories, mustard and coffee powder, cream" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>10: roasted suckling pig, chicories, mustard and coffee powder, cream</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/11.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/11.jpg" alt="11: strawberry with pop rocks, candied apple, pineapple" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>11: strawberry with pop rocks, candied apple, pineapple</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The final savory dish was a roasted suckling pig with mustard greens and a coffee-powdered cream. The dish was alright, a bit gamey but the crisp of the skin provided strong textural contrast with the more easily broken down meat and the chewier mustard greens. The coffee powder was interesting, but overpowered mostly by the sticky sauce. It was decadent, creamy, but a bit too “porky” <strong><em>(3/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>We then replaced the middle fixture with a ball with fruits on sticks. These were simple but absolutely delicious. The strawberries were coated with pop rocks, which was especially refreshing. The apple had become almost translucent after it seemed to be soaked in sugar water and was aptlysweet. The pineapple was also tart and sweet, without being overly sour <strong><em>(4/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/12-A.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/12-A.jpg" alt="12-A: almond, sugar, honey, water, egg white, olive oil, capers" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>12-A: almond, sugar, honey, water, egg white, olive oil, capers</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/12-B.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/12-B.jpg" alt="12-B: warm chocolate tart, crispy seaweed and ginger perfume" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>12-B: warm chocolate tart, crispy seaweed and ginger perfume</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/13.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/13.jpg" alt="13: white chocolate lemon ice cream bon bon, tea matcha chocolate, dark chocolate" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>13: white chocolate lemon ice cream bon bon, tea matcha chocolate, dark chocolate</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>Finally, we had the choice of dessert. I opted for the “Almond Mozzarella,” a candied shell of sugar that encased a foamy, sweet honey, olive oil, and caper mix. Taking a smell, it was exactly akin to a ball of mozzarella, and it came with a tag describing the mozzarella’s “origin.” Unfortunately, this was hit or miss for me. The exterior stuck to my teeth and was a bit chalky, while the taste was too sweet or had too strong of an olive oil and caper flavor. Still, points are given for the interestingness of the idea <strong><em>(2/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>The other option was a simple warm chocolate tart. This was described as okay, with the ginger being a tad strong. It is worth noting that at this point, we were all incredibly full, and unable to fully enjoy and finish the desserts.</p>

<p>The petit fours were quite nice. The lemon ice cream was the right sweetness and chilled. The matcha was rich and sweet, while the dark chocolate had strong flavors <strong><em>(3/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p><a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/00.jpg" class="glightbox"><img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/00.jpg" alt="smyth_menu" /></a></p>

<h2 id="bbb">BBB</h2>

<figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/le_calandre/08-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/le_calandre/08-02.jpg" alt="08-02: veal broth, cream, saffron, licorice, lime, grilled lemon, lemon zest" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08-02: veal broth, cream, saffron, licorice, lime, grilled lemon, lemon zest</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p><em>08-02</em>, the “Risotto ‘Passi D’Oro’” was the standout dish for me for its complexity while elevating a more authentic Italian dish. For me, it represented Le Calandre’s ability to truly elevate the flavor profile of a more simple dish, risotto, while having a clear inspiration in the Uffizi sculpture, all while looking like a true work of art. The clear attention to detail when constructing the flavor profiles, the perfect cooking techniques, and the adherance to Italian cuisine make this a hit for me.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Creative" /><category term="Contemporary" /><category term="Rubano" /><category term="Italy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smyth (***)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/food_blog/posts/2024-05-29-smyth" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smyth (***)" /><published>2024-05-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food_blog/posts/smyth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/food_blog/posts/2024-05-29-smyth"><![CDATA[<!--more-->

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Rating</strong></td>
      <td><em>Overall</em> <strong><em>3.2/5</em></strong><br /> (Taste 3.5/5, Presentation 2/5, Ambience 4.5/5)</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Cost</strong></td>
      <td>$325pp</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Location</strong></td>
      <td>Chicago, IL, USA</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Head Chef</strong></td>
      <td>John Shields, Karen Urie Shields</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>TL;DR</strong></td>
      <td>a creative celebration of forest and sea in a casual but attentive environment</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<figure style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/restaurant.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/restaurant.jpg" alt="" style="width: 50%; display: block; margin: 0 auto;" />
  </a>
  
</figure>

<p>Nestled in the West Loop, stepping into Smyth, you are invited into an assuming layout with an open kitchen that lacks the stuffiness of many other Michelin starred restaurants. The wait staff are friendly and the ambience invites an air of warmth with its open kitchen. At the time of dining, Smyth had been awarded its third star for the first time.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/01.jpg" alt="01: sapote amazake with edible pineapple leaf" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>01: sapote amazake with edible pineapple leaf</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/02.jpg" alt="02: kelp, spot prawn, fennel, dill, basil, tart" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>02: kelp, spot prawn, fennel, dill, basil, tart</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/03.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/03.jpg" alt="03: quail egg, puff, seaweed, yolk sauce" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>03: quail egg, puff, seaweed, yolk sauce</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>To start off, as a precursor to the rest of the courses each with a somewhat Japanese flair, we were presented with the slightly alcoholic, fermented amazake with fruity pineapple notes and a large sprig of pineapple leaf. It was fresh, fruity, and provided good sweetness to begin with <strong><em>(3.5/5)</em></strong>. The tart had a bit of an overwhelmingly herbal flavor with the fennel and dill but these flavors overall went well with the kelp and the prawn, which provided a mushier textural contrast <strong><em>(3/5)</em></strong>. The quail egg dish provided a strong burst of flavor as the yolk exploded while the other ingredients were a bit more muted <strong><em>(3/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/04.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/04.jpg" alt="04: Dungeness crab, jackfruit" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>04: Dungeness crab, jackfruit</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/05.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/05.jpg" alt="05: crab kani custard, passionfruit, miso, amazake" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>05: crab kani custard, passionfruit, miso, amazake</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The following two dishes held with more seafood - the Dungeness crab bite was akin to eating fruit with a briny crab aftertaste. The jackfruit largely dictated the texture but there was a good mix of saltiness and sweetness in the bite <strong><em>(3.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>The crab custard, almost a chawanmushi, was one of the best courses, fusing a rich crab flavor with passionfruit for intense umami and sweetness in every bite. The consistency was soft and delicate, but very savory. It came with an interesting slanted, wooden spoon to aid in getting all the corners of the square plate <strong><em>(4.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/06.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/06.jpg" alt="06: spring onion jelly, lobster consommé, rhubarb" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>06: spring onion jelly, lobster consommé, rhubarb</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/07.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/07.jpg" alt="07: rose butter, artichoke vinaigrette, black walnut sauce, caviar" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>07: rose butter, artichoke vinaigrette, black walnut sauce, caviar</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>From here, if the previous dishes were ocean-themed, the next four seemed to be more land- and earth-themed. The following onion dish was largely forgettable. The onions themselves roasted well and tart, but at the end of the day, they were simply just well prepared onions. The lobster consommé did not provide too much support for flavor <strong><em>(2/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>The caviar dash had a very odd presentation - it was caviar stuck to the side and slowly sliding down into the walnut sauce. In my opinion, this seemed a bit messy and unrefined; we were given almonds and rose butter to alternate enjoying the caviar with, and while they both were pleasant, the rose butter had a much stronger, richer flavor, providing decent contrast <strong><em>(2/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/08.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/08.jpg" alt="08: avocado, eucalyptus, peanut milk, green apple, slushie" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08: avocado, eucalyptus, peanut milk, green apple, slushie</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/09.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/09.jpg" alt="09: buckwheat amazake, asparagus tips, young spruce, asparagus purée" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>09: buckwheat amazake, asparagus tips, young spruce, asparagus purée</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>We were presented with an intermittent palate cleanser, which was effective and fresh. It combined the apple, eucalyptus, and avocado to provide an earthy dish with a peanut milk bed, a bit like a vegetable ice cream. The flavors were subtle and inoffensive, with the iciness and creaminess standing out <strong><em>(3/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>The following asparagus dish fell a bit flat. The cream sauce and purée were just fine, if not a bit tart, and the asparagus tips were properly cooked and nicely textured but lacked much beyond their initial flavor. The inedible spruce was also a bit strange <strong><em>(1.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/10.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/10.jpg" alt="10: steamed brook trout, kombu, congee, seaweed, turnip juice braise, soy glaze" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>10: steamed brook trout, kombu, congee, seaweed, turnip juice braise, soy glaze</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/11-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/11-01.jpg" alt="11-01: lamb multiple ways with lamb tongue draped over lamb rack, fried lamb fat on top, foie gras, lamb liver sausage" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>11-01: lamb multiple ways with lamb tongue draped over lamb rack, fried lamb fat on top, foie gras, lamb liver sausage</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/11-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/11-02.jpg" alt="11-02: milk bread with sourdough, lamb heart sauce with habañero peppers" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>11-02: milk bread with sourdough, lamb heart sauce with habañero peppers</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>I was a big fan of the rainbow trout. The meat’s consistency after being cooked was almost gelatinous, in stark contrast to its flaky skin and kombu. Laying atop the congee allowed the rice to soak up much of the sauce and flavor. The soy glaze was sweet and went well with the bed of turnip juice braise <strong><em>(4/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Their next dish was “Lamb in Many Ways,” where the rack was notably delicious and tender while the sausage was unremarkable but savory, meaty, and salty. The fried lamb fat was also crispy <strong><em>(3.5/5)</em></strong>. The milk bread was fresh, fluffy, and warm, covered in a sweet glaze. It accompanied the lamb heart and habañero sauce well, forming a very unique set of ingredients to combine sweetness with spiciness and tang. I was impressed with Smyth’s willingness to try different combinations of ingredients and look to provide contrast in flavors and textures <strong><em>(4/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/12.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/12.jpg" alt="12: cheese, honey, pineapple, goat's milk yogurt" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>12: cheese, honey, pineapple, goat's milk yogurt</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/13-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/13-01.jpg" alt="13-01: banana custard shaped like a banana made with overripe banana peel oil, kombu braised in fruit, fruit demiglace" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>13-01: banana custard shaped like a banana made with overripe banana peel oil, kombu braised in fruit, fruit demiglace</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/13-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/13-02.jpg" alt="13-02: black walnut truffle with caramel, bits of black walnut" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>13-02: black walnut truffle with caramel, bits of black walnut</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>Onto dessert, the goat cheese texture was just like a perfectly chilled ice cream and the tartness provided by the pineapple with the sweetness of the honey fit together well <strong><em>(3.5/5)</em></strong>. Their banana dish was creative, essentially reconstructing the fruit in novel ways. The custard flavor was strong and we were instructed to bite once into the walnut truffle, finish the “banana,” and finally revisit the truffle, maintaining up its sweetness. This “reconstruction” effectively brought out the banana flavor while rotating with the nuttier truffle mixed well. The sweet, chewy kombu was an interesting touch <strong><em>(4/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/14-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/14-01.jpg" alt="14-01: white chocolate ganachee quail eggs, lemon rind, sunflower, tart" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>14-01: white chocolate ganachee quail eggs, lemon rind, sunflower, tart</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/14-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/14-02.jpg" alt="14-02: graham cracker shot with ganache, flowers from garden" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>14-02: graham cracker shot with ganache, flowers from garden</figcaption>
  
</figure>

  <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/15.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/15.jpg" alt="15: sea lettuce caramel" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>15: sea lettuce caramel</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>We were presented with ganache “quail eggs” within a woven nest, and while the chocolate part was good, I was not a fan of the strong lemon rind flavor, which was almost overpowering <strong><em>(2/5)</em></strong>. The graham cracker shot had quite a neutral ganache but the flower flavor was a bit stronger than I would’ve liked. I would’ve preferred they introduce a more leading flavor within the ganache and held out on the number of flowers they put on top <strong><em>(2/5)</em></strong>. The sea lettuce caramel tasted of seaweed and evoked flavors similar to that of Japanese snacks <strong><em>(3/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Additionally, throughout our meal, the service was especially excellent as left- or right-handedness, towels, and dish explanations were handled with care. It was evident how attentive our waiters and waitresses were even compared to the 3 Michelin star standard.</p>

<p><a href="../assets/image/smyth/00.jpg" class="glightbox"><img src="../assets/image/smyth/00.jpg" alt="smyth_menu" /></a></p>

<h2 id="bbb">BBB</h2>

<figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/smyth/05.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/smyth/05.jpg" alt="05: crab kani custard, passionfruit, miso, amazake" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>05: crab kani custard, passionfruit, miso, amazake</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p><em>05</em> was my favorite of the dishes at Smyth. The Asian influenced chawanmushi had an exceptional balance of sweetness, savoriness, and saltiness and showed how a creative choice of ingredients can yield new ways to enjoy dishes.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Contemporary" /><category term="Creative" /><category term="Chicago" /><category term="United States of America" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alinea (***)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/food_blog/posts/2023-10-09-alinea" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alinea (***)" /><published>2023-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food_blog/posts/alinea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/food_blog/posts/2023-10-09-alinea"><![CDATA[<!--more-->

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Rating</strong></td>
      <td><em>Overall</em> <strong><em>3.4/5</em></strong> <br />(Taste 2/5, Presentation 5/5, Ambience 3.5/5)</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Cost</strong></td>
      <td>$435pp</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Location</strong></td>
      <td>Chicago, IL, USA</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Head Chef</strong></td>
      <td>Grant Achatz</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>TL;DR</strong></td>
      <td>engaging experience with whimsical fare that tests boundaries of gastronomy</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<figure style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/restaurant.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/restaurant.jpg" alt="" style="width: 50%; display: block; margin: 0 auto;" />
  </a>
  
</figure>

<p>Following a day of work, I had the opportunity to dine at Alinea. The restaurant is tucked in a relatively quiet area of Old Town with an easily overlooked facade. We were seated at The Gallery where we were brought in to a dimly lit room with a long, communal table filled with glass flora.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/01-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/01-01.jpg" alt="01-01: trout roe, green beans, and cream tart, cake, sunflower ball" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>01-01: trout roe, green beans, and cream tart, cake, sunflower ball</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/01-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/01-02.jpg" alt="01-02: vegetable wand" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>01-02: vegetable wand</figcaption>
  
</figure>

      <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/01-03.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/01-03.jpg" alt="01-03: champagne" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>01-03: champagne</figcaption>
  
</figure>

      <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/02.jpg" alt="02: garden gazpacho in glass flower, pistil spoon" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>02: garden gazpacho in glass flower, pistil spoon</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The amuse-bouche assortment was so-so, having a interesting textural contrasts between the crispy tart (itself having popping roe and and the snappy green beans), the softer cake, and the condensed sunflower ball <strong><em>(2/5)</em></strong>. Next, the vegetable wand was interesting to look at, but frankly, I didn’t even get to taste this before it was whisked away <strong><em>(1.5/5)</em></strong>. We were also handed a complimentary glass of champagne <strong><em>(2/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Lastly, the garden gazpacho was served to us within a fragile, glass-blown flower with the pistil serving as a spoon. The flowers were extremely interesting to eat out of, enhacing the idea of delicacy, but the soup was not good. The consistency was akin to shaved ice and tasted much too sharp and sour  <strong><em>(1/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Of note, throughout our meal, there was a large stone fixture of a fountain containing what had been presumed to be water. After some story-telling, the waiter asked for two volunteers to assist in pouring two jugs of liquid into said fountain; I obliged, helping with the creation of a later drink.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/03-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/03-01.jpg" alt="03-01: cobbler with walnut cream, quince" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>03-01: cobbler with walnut cream, quince</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/03-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/03-02.jpg" alt="03-02: with peach and country ham" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>03-02: with peach and country ham</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/03-03.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/03-03.jpg" alt="03-03: sherry from pouring pitchers into a fountain" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>03-03: sherry from pouring pitchers into a fountain</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>Following this, we were quickly ushered into the kitchen where we witnessed the construction of the cobbler dish. Chefs sliced cured ham, cut precise pieces of peach, and assembled a solid yet forgettable dish. It again featured contrasting textures as well as combined nuttiness, umami, and syrupy-sweetness from the walnut, ham, and peach, respectively <strong><em>(3/5)</em></strong>. To compliment the dish, we were served a sherry from the fountain: our creation from just a few minutes ago <strong><em>(2/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/04.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/04.jpg" alt="04: caviar, walnut, tapioca" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>04: caviar, walnut, tapioca</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/05.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/05.jpg" alt="05: apple cider, celery juice in a horseradish shell" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>05: apple cider, celery juice in a horseradish shell</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>Upon return to the gallery, the dining room is completely transformed, where it’s well lit and tables are separated. Our first dish is a palm of caviar and walnut, where custom-made glass blown “shells” serve as our plate. Briny and nutty, this was an innovative take to combine all of our senses by involving the tactility of our palms <strong><em>(3/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Next was a “shot” of apple cider and celery juice in a horseradish shell. Personally, I did not enjoy the sour flavors, but it was at least interesting breaking up the horseradish “wax” shell in my mouth to reveal a cool liquid inside <strong><em>(1.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/06.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/06.jpg" alt="06: potato ball speared over cold potato, truffle, parmesan, vichyssoise" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>06: potato ball speared over cold potato, truffle, parmesan, vichyssoise</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/07-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/07-01.jpg" alt="07-01: black cod with potato chips" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>07-01: black cod with potato chips</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/07-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/07-02.jpg" alt="07-02: ashed onion and mint dip" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>07-02: ashed onion and mint dip</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The next dish was the classic “Hot Potato Cold Potato,” and upon removing the spear, you get a sharp contrast of textures and temperatures in a buttery, comforting, and yet fleeting slurp. The combination of the vichyssoise, Parmesan, truffle and potato forms was very imaginative and it was made clear why this is a staple <strong><em>(4.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Next we had the black cod with potato chips and onion and mint dip. It was smoky and soft, and the onion dip was addictive <strong><em>(4/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/08-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/08-01.jpg" alt="08-01: 'sardine' eggplants" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08-01: 'sardine' eggplants</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/08-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/08-02.jpg" alt="08-02: butter over rye crisp" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08-02: butter over rye crisp</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/08-03.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/08-03.jpg" alt="08-03: herbs" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08-03: herbs</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/08-04.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/08-04.jpg" alt="08-04: egg yolk and pickled vegetables" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08-04: egg yolk and pickled vegetables</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/08-05.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/08-05.jpg" alt="08-05: assembled crisp" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>08-05: assembled crisp</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The subsequent “sardine” eggplants were quite tough and while an interesting concept, it fell short on the flavor department for me. Savory and atop a buttery crisp, it felt difficult to eat <strong><em>(1.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/09-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/09-01.jpg" alt="09-01: biscuit hidden within golden duck" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>09-01: biscuit hidden within golden duck</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/09-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/09-02.jpg" alt="09-02: with blueberry jam, foie gras" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>09-02: with blueberry jam, foie gras</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The biscuit was warm, buttery, and flaky. The two jams provided good contrast with sweetness, tartness, and richness <strong>(3.5/5)</strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/10.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/10.jpg" alt="10: squab with dried vegetables, rehydrated in jous" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>10: squab with dried vegetables, rehydrated in jous</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/11.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/11.jpg" alt="11: chicken wing with sesame seeds and gooseberry sauce, gooseberry with matsutake mushrooms, rice block with uni and gooseberry" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>11: chicken wing with sesame seeds and gooseberry sauce, gooseberry with matsutake mushrooms, rice block with uni and gooseberry</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The squab was perfectly cooked, hitting on its tenderness and flavor. It had the right amount of gaminess and the rehydrating jous was rich and umami, providing textural contrast when the crunchy vegetables were applied <strong><em>(4.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>The next set of courses were gooseberry themed, and for the uni they again brought out a tactile bowl for an interesting sensation. All three played on the use of sweetness and savoriness, with my only complaint being my desire for a napkin after the chicken wing. Otherwise, the individual ingredients really stood out, with the individual rice granules tasted and the mushrooms having natural fungal flavor and bite <strong><em>(4/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/12.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/12.jpg" alt="12: black truffle, romaine lettuce, parmesan, all encased in pasta" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>12: black truffle, romaine lettuce, parmesan, all encased in pasta</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/13.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/13.jpg" alt="13: venison, rabbit, apple, onion, served with a stick on fire" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>13: venison, rabbit, apple, onion, served with a stick on fire</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The following was another Alinea classic called the “Truffle Explosion,” where we were advised to eat with our mouths shut to get all of the flavor. This truly lived up to the hype; inside was a decadent amount of truffle juice, with the other ingredients primarily providing texture <strong><em>(4.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>This was followed up with a stranger looking dish consisting of a fried meatball attached to a flaming stick. The meatball consisted of numerous different meats, apple, and onion, but for me, the flavors mixed a bit together. The presentation was interesting, if not a little out of place, and the seasoning was done well, but this was not a standout <strong><em>(3/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/14-01.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/14-01.jpg" alt="14-01: Australian wagyu short rib, parsnip chip, saffron dot, turnip mash" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>14-01: Australian wagyu short rib, parsnip chip, saffron dot, turnip mash</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/14-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/14-02.jpg" alt="14-02: jameed" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>14-02: jameed</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>Next, we were introduced to dishes that relied heavily on parsnip flavor. First, we were presented with a plate of wagyu short rib and various root vegetable chips and mash. Next, we were introduced to a mysterious large white mound which was later revealed to be jameed, a solidified Middle Eastern yogurt.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/14-03.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/14-03.jpg" alt="14-03: shaved jameed atop short rib" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>14-03: shaved jameed atop short rib</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/15.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/15.jpg" alt="15: parsnip pureé with roasted onion" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>15: parsnip pureé with roasted onion</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>The jameed was shaved over the shortrib, providing a bit of saltiness and tanginess to the cut of meat. The shortrib itself was absolutely delicious; it was cooked excellently and had melt-in-your-mouth texture. The sides to this dish were okay and didn’t overwhelm the flavors of the meat <strong><em>(4/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>On the side, the parsnip puree was pungent and had crunchy nibs, but the plate itself was somewhat forgettable. The flavor of the dish, with a funk similar to an onion, lingered in your mouth <strong><em>(2/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem;">
   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/16.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/16.jpg" alt="16: Hubba Bubba infused tea, tapioca pearls, crème fraîche, hibiscus jam, thai long peppercorn" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>16: Hubba Bubba infused tea, tapioca pearls, crème fraîche, hibiscus jam, thai long peppercorn</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/17-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/17-02.jpg" alt="17-02: liquid nitrogen banana ice cream, strawberry and banana cream with chocolate sauce, pineapple turnover cake with butterscotch crumbs" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>17-02: liquid nitrogen banana ice cream, strawberry and banana cream with chocolate sauce, pineapple turnover cake with butterscotch crumbs</figcaption>
  
</figure>

   <figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/18.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/18.jpg" alt="18: green apple toffee balloon, helium" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>18: green apple toffee balloon, helium</figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>

<p>Dessert was an amazing experience. The first tea served in a tube tasted exactly of Hubba Bubba and set the tone for the playfulness of the following dishes. Held together at the ends with just crème fraîche, the dessert was super interesting to taste <strong><em>(4/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>“Painted Dessert” was a spectacle to behold as lights dimmed and our table was shrouded with dry ice. As one chef came by, assembling the art using various components and then smashing the liquid nitrogen banana ice cream, one was just holding their breath as the choreography took place and we ate directly off the table. Additionally, every component was tasty, not too sweet, and had quite large portion sizes. The only room for improvement would be to in the depth of the individual flavors <strong><em>(4.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p>Lastly, we were handed a fully edible balloon of apple toffee with helium to play with. It was sweet, but the main appeal was the high-pitched voices from the helium <strong><em>(3.5/5)</em></strong>.</p>

<p><a href="../assets/image/alinea/00.jpg" class="glightbox"><img src="../assets/image/alinea/00.jpg" alt="alinea_menu" /></a></p>

<h2 id="bbb">BBB</h2>

<figure>
  <a href="../assets/image/alinea/17-02.jpg" class="glightbox">
    <img src="../assets/image/alinea/17-02.jpg" alt="17-02: liquid nitrogen banana ice cream, strawberry and banana cream with chocolate sauce, pineapple turnover cake with butterscotch crumbs" style="width: 100%;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption>17-02: liquid nitrogen banana ice cream, strawberry and banana cream with chocolate sauce, pineapple turnover cake with butterscotch crumbs</figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p><em>17-02</em>, “Painted Dessert,” has to be the standout at Alinea for me. I think it really encapsulates the best of what Alinea has to offer: an immensely entertaining dish with novel ways to eat, where the selling point isn’t necessarily the intensity or complexity of its flavors, but rather the entire eating experience.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Creative" /><category term="Modern Cuisine" /><category term="Chicago" /><category term="United States of America" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>